W. R. "Bob" Poage Personal papers, Inclusive: 1766-2008, undated, Bulk: 1937-1978
Baylor University Libraries
W. R. "Bob" Poage Personal papers
Inclusive: 1766-2008, undated, Bulk: 1937-1978
Baylor University Libraries https://www.baylor.edu/library/
1F
Poage, W. R. (William Robert), 1899 - 1987
122 document boxes and 88 oversized boxes.
The W. R. "Bob" Poage Personal papers cover the entirety of Poage's life (1899-1987) and extend beyond to chronicle his father's life, as well as media coverage of Bob Poage's passing. The bulk of these papers span his career as a U.S. Representative (1937-1978), but the collection also includes artifacts from his childhood, law practice, and family.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
William Robert “Bob” Poage, the son of William Allen Poage and Helen Wheeler Conger, was born on December 28, 1899, in Waco, Texas. The Poage family moved to Throckmorton County shortly thereafter, where William A. Poage worked as a rancher and cattleman. The Poages eventually returned to Waco in 1913. Five years later, in 1918, Poage graduated from Waco High School and joined the U.S. Navy as an apprentice seaman during the waning months of World War I.
After the war, Poage briefly attended classes at the University of Texas and the University of Colorado at Boulder before enrolling at Baylor University. In 1921, he graduated with a bachelor’s degree in Geology. Poage taught geology from 1922 to 1924, while simultaneously working on his law degree. In 1924, he earned his law degree from Baylor University and gained admittance to the Texas Bar.
In that same year, Poage ran for political office, winning a seat in the Texas House of Representatives. He served in the Texas House from 1925 to 1929, all while practicing law in Waco and teaching at Baylor Law School. In 1928, Poage attempted but lost a bid for a seat in the Texas Senate and briefly returned to civilian life. In 1931, Poage sought to fill a Senate seat vacated by Edgar Witt. He won the special election this time, ultimately serving in the Texas Senate from 1931 to 1937.
Striving to increase his political influence, Poage tried to unseat U.S. Representative O. H. Cross of the 11th Congressional District of Texas. Poage lost in 1934, but succeeded in defeating Cross in 1936. It was to be the start of a long-tenured career for the Texas Democrat. On February 14, 1938, amidst his political successes, Poage married Frances Lenoir Cotton.
Poage served in the U.S. House from 1937 until his retirement in 1978, often running unopposed in the biennial elections. Drawing from his childhood experiences and education, Poage championed life in rural America, seeking improvements such as water and telephone services and helping to establish the Rural Electrification Administration. Often referred to as “Mr. Agriculture”, Poage was a key member of the House Agriculture Committee from 1941 to 1978, chairing the committee from 1967 to 1974. Upon his retirement from the House in 1978, Poage was succeeded by Democrat Marvin Leath.
The W. R. Poage Legislative Library was opened in September 1979 in honor of Representative Poage and serves as the repository for his personal and congressional papers. Poage wrote five books during his lifetime including three in retirement: After the Pioneers (1969), Politics-Texas Style (1974), How We Lived (1980), McLennan County Before 1980 (1981), and his autobiography, My First 85 Years (1985).
Poage passed away during open-heart surgery in Temple, Texas, on January 3, 1987, and is buried in Waco’s Oakwood Cemetery.
Scope and Content
The W. R. "Bob" Poage Personal papers contain items from 1766 to 2008, with the bulk of the materials ranging from 1937 to 1978 (Poage's tenure in the U.S. House of Representatives). The collection consists of materials collected by Poage across his lifetime and are comprised of correspondence, legal documents, newspaper clippings, photographs, speeches, and other personal materials. The collection is arranged into seven different series that reflect different biographical topics or formats.
Series I. Biographical Materials is the most expansive series in the collection and contains materials related to Poage's personal life and family. This series includes a variety of formats, including family and business correspondence, financial and legal documents, manuscripts from his published books, newspaper clippings, certificates, and more.
Series II. Law Practice is the smallest series and focuses on Poage's work as a lawyer. This series is mostly correspondence with his clients and relevant legal documents. His practice ran from 1924 to approximately 1937, and primarily dealt with delinquent notes and collections, land and mineral leases, logistics companies, and probate law.
Series III. Photographs depicts Poage's personal and professional life, portraits from friends and colleagues, travels, illustrations and decorative paintings, event coverage, and more.
Series IV. Speeches consists of transcripts from most of Poage's speeches as a Representative. Poage spoke at many conferences and events during his tenure in Congress where he was a staunch advocate for farming and agricultural laborers. These transcripts come from radio and television speeches, keynote addresses, press releases, and excerpts from The Congressional Record.
Series V. Travel is split into two subseries and covers materials related to his travels as a Representative. Poage traveled frequently in his career as an appointee to the Interparliamentary Union and as a member of the House Committee on Agriculture. Subseries I. Poage Trips consists mostly of correspondence, itineraries, official documents, and other personal or government papers related to the logistics of his travels. Subseries II. Travel Information contains mostly brochures, postcards, stickers, maps, and other mementos collected from his travels.
Series VI. Three-Dimensional Artifacts consists of oversized and oddly shaped items collected during the lifetime of W. R. Poage. A significant amount of this series consists of plaques awarded to Poage from various organizations, but also includes an assorted button collection, Congressional license plates, books, silver dining materials, Stetson hats, and more.
Series VII. Audiovisual Materials contains a wide array of media formats. Bob Poage and his nephew Scott Poage collected over 4,000 slides from their travels around the world. The series also contains over 90 audio and film reels, many of which capture Representative Poage discussing prominent political issues of the time including care of the environment, the Agriculture Committee, civil protests, the seniority system in Congress, food prices, re-election campaigns, and retirement.
Arrangement
The W. R. "Bob" Poage papers have been processed previously, most recently in 1995. Detailed finding aids and folder listings already existed prior to this latest round of processing.
Due to the large size of the collection, the W. R. "Bob" Poage papers are being divided into six new collections based on the existing series outline. The materials in the Personal papers were originally housed in Boxes #1022-1024, 1427-1501, 1572-1576, 1579-1633, and 1635-1667. Some loose materials have also been integrated with these files.
The Personal papers are now arranged into seven series based on the original organization: I. Biographical Materials, II. Law Practice, III. Photographs, IV. Speeches, V. Travel, VI. Three-Dimensional Artifacts, and VII. Audiovisual Materials.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the W. R. Poage Legislative Library in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 1F. Acquired 1961-08-01
Related Resources
Items in related collections
W. R. "Bob" Poage U.S. Government papers, Inclusive: 1912-1981, undated, Bulk: 1960-1978
W. R. "Bob" Poage State Legislative papers, Inclusive: 1923-1971, undated, Bulk: 1933-1936
W. R. "Bob" Poage Texas Development papers, Inclusive: 1913-1979, undated, Bulk: 1946-1978
W. R. "Bob" Poage Campaign papers, Inclusive: 1898-1997, undated, Bulk: 1936-1978
Related references
Duggan, Laura Woolsey. “Poage, William Robert.” Handbook of Texas Online, accessed June 11, 2019.
Pearson, Richard. “Former U.S. Rep. William R. (Bob) Poage Dies.” Washington Post, January 4, 1987.
Poage, W. R. My First 85 Years. Waco, TX: Texian Press, 1985.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Poage, Frances C. 1901-1983.; Poage, W. A. (William Allen), 1855-1920.; Poage, W. R. (William Robert), 1899-1987.
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- History.; Baylor University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Inter-parliamentary Union; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Agriculture--Officials and employees.; United States. Congress. House.
Places
McLennan County (Tex.) -- Politics and government.; McLennan County (Tex.); Texas -- History.; Texas -- Politics and government.; Waco (Tex.).
Subjects
Agriculture -- Texas.; Agriculture -- United States.; Genealogy.; Lawyers -- Texas.; Legislators -- United States.; United States -- Politics and government.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Legal documents.; Maps.; Photographs.; Realia.; Scrapbooks.; Speeches.
- Biographical Materials, 1838-2008, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This expansive series covers all personal materials related to Bob Poage and his family. The series includes a variety of materials, including family correspondence, financial documents, manuscripts from his published books, newspaper clippings, and more. Items are arranged chronologically with undated materials appearing at the front of the series. Folders with date ranges or broad dates are arranged at the front of the arrangement, followed by folders with more specific dates.
  The documents in this series are in good condition overall. Many fragile or acidic documents have been preserved or copied, but several fragile books remain.
  - Ancient Order of the Stouthearted Citizen, Citation, undated (Box 131 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Baylor Founder’s Club, Certificate of Appreciation, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Belton Chamber of Commerce, Certificate of Appreciation, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Blackhorse Brigade, Membership Certificate, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Card Files, Business Cards (455 cards), undated (Box 128 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Card Files, Table Placards (24 cards), undated (Box 130 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Catfish Farmers of Texas, Membership Certificate, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Central Power Electric Cooperative, Good Turn Award, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Certificate of Appreciation for Public Law 89-544, undated (Box 131 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Christmas Card from President Jimmy and Rosalynn Carter, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - County of Los Angeles, Citation, undated (Box 131 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Frances C. Poage to Helen C. Poage, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Frances C. Poage, Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Cards, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Guest Editorial for National Police Officer’s Association, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Helen C. Poage, Wallet, undated (Box 131 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - “How We Lived,” Dr. B.T.A. Freeman Interview, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - “How We Lived,” Dr. Emma Louise McDonald Harrison Interview and Materials, Notes and Edited Drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - “How We Lived,” Drafts of Dedication and Foreword, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - “How We Lived,” Draft with Edits, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - “How We Lived,” Ed and George Smajstrla Interviews and Edited Draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - “How We Lived,” Fowler C. West Interview and Edited Drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - “How We Lived,” Galley Proof, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - “How We Lived,” Gus Levy Interview and Edited Draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - “How We Lived,” Homer Warren Interview and Edited Draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - “How We Lived,” How We Learned Drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - “How We Lived,” How We/Life Differed Drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - “How We Lived,” How We Traveled Drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - “How We Lived,” How We Worked Drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - “How We Lived,” James M. Warner Interview, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - “How We Lived,” John Hastings Interview and Edited Drafts, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - “How We Lived,” Kathy Domingus Interview and Edited Draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - “How We Lived,” Lavonia Jenkins Barnes Interview and Edited Draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - “How We Lived,” Mary Long Armstead Interview and Edited Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - “How We Lived,” Proof and Notes, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - “How We Lived,” Ray Rabroker Interview and Edited Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - “How We Lived,” Rough Draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - “How We Lived,” Ruben M. Santos Article, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - “How We Lived,” Walter Dossett Interview and Edited Draft, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - “How We Lived,” What We Ate Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - “How We Lived,” What We Wore Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - “How We Lived,” Where We Lived Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - “How We Lived,” Where We Played Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - “How We Lived,” W. R. Poage Interview and Edited Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Maps, Signed “Robert Poage” and “General Robert E. Lee”, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 1 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 2 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 3 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 4 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 5 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 6 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 7 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 8 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 9 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 10 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 11 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 12 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 13 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 14 Edited Drafts (1 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 14 Edited Drafts (2 of 2), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 15 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 16 Edited Drafts (1 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 16 Edited Drafts (2 of 3), undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 16 Edited Drafts (3 of 3), undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 17 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 18 Edited Drafts (1 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 18 Edited Drafts (2 of 2), undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter 19 Edited Drafts, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Chapter Outlines, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Manuscripts, Chapters 1-5, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Manuscripts, Chapters 6-10, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Manuscripts, Chapters 11-15, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Manuscripts, Chapters 16-17, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Manuscripts, Chapters 18-19 and Index, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Maps, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Summary of Remaining Questions, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Mineral Wells, Texas Chamber of Commerce, Resolution, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Critiques from Proofreaders, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, A Candidate for Congress, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, A Congressional Freshman, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, A Conservative?, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, A Dozen (Tall) Texans, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, A New Day/Change of Command, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, A Yellow Dog Democrat, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Baylor, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Eight Presidents, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Forebearers, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Frances: My Great Lady, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Health, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, How We Lived, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Index, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Law and Land, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Life on the Lazy ’Leven, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Mr. Chairman, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, My First Trips Abroad, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, My Staff, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Religion, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, School Days, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Texas Legislature, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, The Agriculture Committee, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, The Eleventh District, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, The Interparliamentary Union, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, The Ranch Country, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, The Third House, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Twilight and Evening Star, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, Where We Lived, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Edited Drafts, World War I, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Full Manuscript, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Galley Proof, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Photograph Outlines, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Proof, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - “My First 85 Years,” Rough Manuscript, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - National Aeronautic Association, Membership Certificate, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Novelty Cards and Letters, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Paul Quinn College Century Club, Membership Certificate, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Addendums to Manuscript, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Galley Proofs, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Graphics Sketches, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Manuscripts (1 of 8), undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Manuscripts (2 of 8), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Manuscripts (3 of 8), undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Manuscripts (4 of 8), undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Manuscripts (5 of 8), undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Manuscripts (6 of 8), undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Manuscripts (7 of 8), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - “Politics Texas Style,” Manuscripts (8 of 8), undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Registration for Rolex Watch, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Salomon Family Christmas Card, undated (Box 131 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Songs, Poems, Anecdotes, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Texas and Southwestern Cattle Raisers Association, Certificate of Appreciation, undated (Box 131 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Texas State Society, Certificate of Appreciation, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Untitled Geography Book of Robert Lee Poage, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - W. A. Poage, Campaign Cards, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - W. A. Poage, Universalist Theological Literature, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Waco Optimist Club Luncheon, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - West, Texas Chamber of Commerce, Citation, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - “Wife’s Illness Causes Poage to Return to Waco,” Newspaper Clipping, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - W. R. Poage Stationery, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - “McLennan County — Before 1980,” Abstracts, Causes, and Wills for Chapter 8 Research, 1838-1916 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - State of Alabama, Legal Documents, 1845-1857 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - “Barnes’ Complete Geography,” Book of Helen Conger, 1885 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Mary C. Billings, Valentine’s Day Card, 1885 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - W. A. Poage, Notes and Deposits, 1891-1909 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - W.J. Hood, T.J. England, H.E. Conger, Transfers of Comanche County, Texas Land, 1891-1921 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - “Cowboy’s Day at the Texas Cotton Palace” Program, 1894 November 30 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Poage Family Correspondence, 1895-1911, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - J.P. Brown, Vendor’s Lien Notes, 1897-1900 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - W. A. Poage, City of Waco Tax Receipts, 1897-1910 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - W. A. Poage, Vendor’s Liens, Warranty Deeds, Leases (1 of 2), 1898-1918 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - W. A. Poage, Vendor’s Liens, Warranty Deeds, Leases (2 of 2), 1898-1918 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - W. A. Poage and Helen Conger, Marriage License, 1898 June 8 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Frances C. Poage, Marriage License and Timesheet from Father, 1899-1901 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - W. A. Poage, Delinquent Tax Redemption Receipts, 1899-1902 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - “A Modern English Grammar with Composition,” Book of Robert Lee Poage, 1900 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - R. L. Poage and W. A. Poage, Correspondence, 1900-1913, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - W. R. Poage, “Baby’s Diary”, 1900 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - “Complete Debater’s Manual”, 1903 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - “Our Country’s Readers”, 1906 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Friends and Family, 1906-1937 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - W. A. Poage, General Correspondence, 1906-1913 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Loan Receipts, 1907-1930 (Box 12, Folder 6)